Hi.
I'm Michael Seto, professional photographer, and in this clip we're going to talk about selecting and using a tripod for jewelry photography.
First of all, when you're shooting jewelry, which is a macro type situation, meaning you're shooting up close, you absolutely need a tripod.
There is no way you're going to be able to shoot something like that and get a very clear and sharp photo without using a tripod, just because you're very close to the subject, any movement will be magnified in the photograph.
As well, you tend to shoot with a slower shutter speed so that also exacerbates any movement.
So let's look at a couple of tripods here.
You can go with a very basic small travel tripod, these are fairly economical.
They come with a little quick detach mechanism that fits on the bottom of your camera.
These will do the job in a pinch, but they're fairly light weight, they will not be as stable as a more heavy-duty tripod like this one.
This is a Manfrotto 055.
It's a nice sturdy tripod.
It's something that a lot of professionals use.
As well, instead of just the standard head on this, this is more of a video head, I use a ball head.
This one is made by Really Right Stuff.
They make some fantastic, very high quality ball heads, probably the Cadillac of ball heads and you really need one of these to, to be able to take a good shot of a piece of jewelry.
So tripod is important, a nice heavy-duty tripod with the good head is a key to a stable camera when doing jewelry photography.